Claire Falkenstein
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, circa 1890-1997, Series 8:; (Box 27-35, 43, 55-56; 9.5 linear feet)
  - Falkenstein with Family and Friends, 1933-1997, 8.2:
    - Claire Falkenstein with Lena Hansen, circa 1993 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Martha Jackson, circa 1965-1969 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Richard McCarthy, circa 1940-1950 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Claire Falkenstein in Venice with Berto Morucchio, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Hal Nelson, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Paul Karlstrom and Susan Lawrence, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Lunch with Sue and David Parry and Elaine Jones, circa 1991 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Falkenstein with Michel Tapie, circa 1957-1966 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Falkenstein with Alan Becky and Susannah Temko, circa 1980 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Falkenstein with Friends, circa 1917-1949 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Falkenstein with Friends, circa 1950-1970, (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 48-49)
    - Falkenstein with Friends, circa 1952-1958 (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Falkenstein with Friends in Europe, circa 1953 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Falkenstein with Friends, circa 1970-1997, (3 folders) (Box 27, Folder 52-54)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at Venice Studio Event, circa 1970 (Box 27, Folder 55)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at Party, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 56)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at July 4th Party, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 57)
    - Claire Falkenstein in Oregon with Friends, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 58)
    - Claire Falkenstein with Friends at NASA Exhibit, circa 1987 (Box 27, Folder 59)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at Christmas Party, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 60)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at Party, circa 1993 (Box 27, Folder 61)
    - Falkenstein with Friends at Studio Event, circa 1993 (Box 27, Folder 62)
    - Claire Falkenstein, Family, Friends, and Travel - Negatives, circa 1930-1960 (Box 27, Folder 63)
    - Claire Falkenstein, Family, Friends, and Travel - Negatives, circa 1930-1960, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - Family and Friends, circa 1890-1997, 8.3:
    This subseries contains images of Falkenstein's family, friends, and colleagues. She is not present in the majority of these photographs. Several images from the 1890s to the 1920s are included in this subseries but they are largely unidentified. Of particular interest are the images of Falkenstein's good friend, May O'Donnell, a dancer and choreographer who studied with Martha Graham. There are also images of Mark Tobey and Michel Tapie.
    Photographs of identified individuals are filed at the beginning of the subseries and unidentified individuals at the end of the subseries.
    - Moo Anderson, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Helen and Frank Bickel (Falkenstein's Sister), 1910, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Vanner Bickel with his Family (Falkenstein's nephew), circa 1933-1967 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Olive Cowell, circa 1969 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Victor Cusack, circa 1980 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Lena Hansen in Venice, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Louis Heyn - Last Visit, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Richard McCarthy (Falkenstein's husband), circa 1929-1950 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Lani, Don, and Natalie Martin (Falkenstein's niece), circa 1980 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Luigi Moretti - Negatives, circa 1951-1968 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - May O'Donnell, circa 1947 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Bob Royston, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Bozidar von Serda, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Michel Tapie, circa 1955-1965 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Susannah Temko, circa 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Mark Tobey, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - May O'Donnell - Negatives, circa 1947 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Susannah Temko - Negatives, circa 1977-1978 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Family and Friends - Unidentified, circa 1890-1940 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Friends - Unidentified, circa 1930-1997, (4 folders) (Box 28, Folder 22-25)
    - Friends - Unidentified - Negatives, circa 1930-1997 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Travel, 1935-1978, 8.4:
    The majority of these files document Falkenstein's many trips to Europe. The general travel files contain unidentified snapshots, probably of Falkenstein's trip to Mexico with her husband in the 1930s.
    - Travel - France, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Travel - Greece 1970 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Travel - Japan, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Travel to Europe - Paris, Luxembourg Gardens, circa 1975 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Travel - Italy, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Travel - General 1935-1945, (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 32-34)
    - Travel - Negatives, circa 1935-1945 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Commissions, 1944-1995, 8.5:
    The photographs in this subseries are a visual complement to the textual records in the commission series. They include images of project construction, as well as photographs of the completed commissions. Photographs of one of Falkenstein's first public fountain commissions, "Structure and Flow #2" at California Federal Savings and Loan, are particularly extensive and include installation photographs. In 1995, the fountain was dismantled and the copper parts were stolen. Images of the deteriorating fountain are also included in these files. In addition, the subseries contains photographs of the gates that Falkenstein designed and built for Peggy Guggenheim's villa in Venice.
    St. Basil Church, the largest commission of Falkenstein's career is also documented in this subseries.
    The files are arranged alphabetically by commission.
    - Tito Bastianello, Window on Grand Canal in Venice, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Joseph Bransten Table, 1948, (2 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 28, Folder 37-38)
    - Robert Buffum, Suspended Fountain, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - California Department of Motor Vehicles, "Traffic Interchange," 1987 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - California Federal Savings and Loan, "Structure and Flow #2" Construction, 1964, (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 41-43)
    - California Federal Savings and Loan, "Structure and Flow #2," 1964-1965, (5 folders) (Box 28, Folder 44-48)
    - California Federal Savings and Loan, "Structure and Flow #2" Installation, 1964, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 49-50)
    - California Federal Savings and Loan, "Structure and Flow #2" - Deterioration of Fountain, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 51)
    - Men's Gymnasium, CSU Fullerton - Relief called "Game Wall," 1965 (Box 28, Folder 52)
    - California State University, Dominquez Hills - Tribute to A. Quincy Jones, Models of "The Forum," circa 1986 (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - California State University, Dominquez Hills - Tribute to A. Quincy Jones, Open Reception of "The Forum," 1986 (Box 28, Folder 54)
    - California State University, Dominquez Hills - Tribute to A. Quincy Jones "The Forum," circa 1986 (Box 28, Folder 55)
    - California State University, Fullerton, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 56)
    - California State University, Long Beach - First International Sculpture Symposium - "U as a Set," 1965, (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 57-58)
    - City of Coos Bay, Oregon - "Signs of the Pacific," 1976 (Box 28, Folder 59)
    - Dallas Conklin "Sign of the Pacific," 1960 (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - David Parry and Associates, circa 1980 (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - Garrett Eckbo and Bob Royston, Hanging Fountain, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - Fine Arts Gallery, San Diego - "Accelerating Point," 1974 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Fresno Mall, California - "Three Fires," 1965-1966, (6 folders) (Box 29, Folder 2-7)
    - Fresno Mall, California - "Leaping Fire," 1966 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Galeria Spazio Stair Screen, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Galerie Stadler Stair Sculpture, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Golden Gateway North, San Francisco - "Tide Pool Fountain," 1983 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Peggy Guggenheim Gate, 1961, (2 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
    - Louis Heyn and Long Beach Museum of Art - "Sculpture and Flow #3," 1969-1971, (14 folders) (Box 29, Folder 14-27)
    - Louis Heyn and Long Beach Museum of Art - "Sculpture and Flow #3" Installation, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Hyland Laboratories, Costa Mesa - "DNA Molecules," 1970, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 29-30)
    - Joseph Magnin Store Interior Fountain, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Laurel Hill Cemetery, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Arthur and Edith Levin Suspended Fountain, 1978-1979 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - The Newquists - "The Sun," circa 1980 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Donald Olsen Mural in Stairwell, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Palm Springs Desert Museum - "Cossman Fountain," 1975 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Phoenix Art Museum Sculpture for Reflecting Pool, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Princess Pignatelli Grotto Gates in Rome, 1957, (Oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - K. Reswick Ring, circa 1973 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Robert Robles, Los Angeles - "Structure and Flow," 1963 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Alix de Rothchild, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Bob Royston Fountain, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Sam Rubenstein Entrance Doors, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Sam Rubenstein - "Tide Pools," 1981 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - John Sadler - "Sun Dial," 1969 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Window Screens, Doors, and Rectory Screens, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Window Screens, Doors, and Rectory Screens, 1968-1969, (3 folders) (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
    - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Window Screens, Doors, and Rectory Screen Construction, 1968-1969, (Oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Side Narthex Gates, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Window Screens, Doors, and Rectory Screens, Negatives, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - St. Luke's Episcopal Church, Long Beach - "Sun Dial," 1969, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 7-8)
    - San Diego Fine Arts Gallery - "Accelerating Point" for Reflecting Pool, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - San Leandro Naval Hospital War Murals, 1944-1945 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Mel and Jerrie Scott Chain, 1949 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Segerstrom Gates, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - South Coast Plaza, Costa Mesa - "Sun Ribbon," 1982, (5 folders) (Box 30, Folder 13-17)
    - Arthur Spitzer - "Signs" Divider between Library and Dining Room, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Louis Stratham, Lone Pine, California - "Fire and Ice" Lamps on Fence and "Structure and Flow #4" Fountain, 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 19-20)
    - Tate Gallery, London - "Point as a Set #26" Homage to Herbert Read, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - University of Southern California, Bing Theater - "Continuum," 1976 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - UCLA, Hilgard Entrance - "Point as a Set #25," 1970 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Eileen Norris Theater - "Film Strip" and "Montage Sections," 1973-1975 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - George Walker - "The Surf: Skeleton of a Wave," 1982 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - John C. Warneke "Wind Modillator," 1947 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - South Coast Plaza, Costa Mesa - "Sun Ribbon" Negatives, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Exhibitions, 1941-1995, 8.6:
    Photographs of exhibitions include openings, installations, artwork, and exhibition sites. Of particular interest are the photographs from Falkenstein's many exhibitions at the San Francisco Museum of Art from 1941 to 1958. These files document Falkenstein's first exhibitions and contain many images of her early sculptures.
    The files are arranged alphabetically by name of gallery or location of exhibition.
    - Art Council, Thousand Oaks, California, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Bolles Gallery, circa 1958 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Bonestell Gallery, circa 1944 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - California State University, Stanislow, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - California Federal Savings and Loan, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Coos Bay Art Museum, Oregon, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - David Anderson Gallery, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - DeYoung Museum, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Esther Robles Gallery, Los Angeles, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Fisher Gallery - "Still Working," 1995 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Fresno Art Center, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 38-39)
    - Galerie Rive Droite, Paris, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Galerie Parnass, Wupertal, Germany, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Galerie Stadler, Paris, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - Gallery Mayer, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Gallery Spazio, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Hemmerdinger Gallery, Palm Desert, California, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 45-46)
    - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1981-1987, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 47-48)
    - Jack Rutberg Fine Arts Gallery, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - Long Beach Museum of Art, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - Loyola Marymount College, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 52)
    - Museum of Women in the Arts, Washington, DC, circa 1993 (Box 30, Folder 53)
    - Neill Gallery, New York, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - New York - Rome Art Foundation, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 55)
    - Oakland Flower Show, 1946-1947 (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - Palm Springs Desert Museum, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - Phoenix Museum of Art, 1967, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Polly Friedlander Gallery, Seattle, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Roberts Art Gallery, Santa Monica, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
    - Salon di Mai, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1941-1958, (5 folders) (Box 31, Folder 7-11)
    - Sherman Foundation, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Thousand Oaks Art Council, Thousand Oaks, California, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Torque Gallery, 1976, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 31, Folder 14-15)
    - Unidentified Exhibitions, circa 1944-1990 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - University Art Gallery, California State University, Riverside, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Werkbund in Berlin, Germany, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Works of Art, circa 1935-1995, 8.7:
    This subseries reflects Falkenstein's extensive visual documentation of her artwork. The files include photographs of the majority of her pieces, including sculpture, drawings, paintings, murals, jewelry, lamps, wallpaper. For the most part, these are images of the artwork only.
    Photographs of identified single art pieces are filed at the beginning of the subseries, followed by media specific files in alphabetically order. The general files, both identified and unidentified works of art, are filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "Accelerating Point," 1975 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Copper Welding Leading to "Accelerating Point," circa 1970 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "Allegory" Detail, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "Chain," 1976 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "Connections," 1983 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - "The Couple," circa 1953 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - "The Cradles," 1975 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - "Envelope" and "Involuting Zero," circa 1935-1995 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - "Fly," 1970 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - "Flora," 1971 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - "Fulcrum," circa 1970 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - "Galactic Transformation," 1968 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - "Generating a Tube," circa 1979 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - "Generation of a Cube," 1979 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - "Homage to Gaudi," 1956 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - "Horses," 1987 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - "Hunger of World," circa 1981 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - "Integration," 1958 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - "Joyful Rectangle" Rejected Submission to San Diego State College Competition, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - "Leda and the Swan," circa 1954-1960 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - "Mosaic," 1938 (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - "Net Structure," 1958 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - "Never Ending Screen," 1971 (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - "Organic Form," circa 1968 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - "Over the Wall," 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - "Other Universes," 1983 (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - "Parade Mask," 1980 (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - "Pasture," 1987 (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - "Point as a Set," circa 1964-1974, (2 folders) (Box 31, Folder 47-48)
    - "Point to Cone," 1975 (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - "Predator," 1985 (Box 31, Folder 50)
    - "Quilt," 1976 (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - "Rolling," 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - "Sculpture in Mahogany," 1951 (Box 31, Folder 53)
    - "Set Structure," 1948 (Box 31, Folder 54)
    - "Sign," 1946 (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - "Sign of the U," 1960 (Box 31, Folder 56)
    - "Sky," circa 1959-1965 (Box 31, Folder 57)
    - "Soaring," 1974 (Box 31, Folder 58)
    - "Spider Structure," 1958 (Box 31, Folder 59)
    - "The Sun" - Several Versions, circa 1955-1974, (5 folders) (Box 31, Folder 60-64)
    - "Sun Dial," 1969 (Box 31, Folder 65)
    - "Tapie's Head," circa 1956 (Box 31, Folder 66)
    - "Tecumseh," circa 1982 (Box 31, Folder 67)
    - "Traveler," 1980 (Box 31, Folder 68)
    - "Truss Structure," 1977 (Box 31, Folder 69)
    - "Vertebra," 1944 (Box 31, Folder 70)
    - "Struttura Grafica," circa 1955-1975 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "U as a Set" or "Sign of the U," circa 1958-1960 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "Vibration," circa 1958-1964 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Bamboo,circa 1970-1978, (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
    - Ceramics, circa 1935-1995, (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
    - Castings, circa 1935-1995 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Collages, circa 1935-1948 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Drawing with Felt Tip Pen, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Drawing with Charcoal, 1979-1981 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Drawings, circa 1983-1993, (5 folders) (Box 32, Folder 12-16)
    - Drawings and Paintings, circa 1935-1995, (22 folders) (Box 32, Folder 17-38)
    - Expanding Screens, circa 1958-1964 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Gates, circa 1957-1972 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Glass, circa 1950-1985 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Glass, circa 1958-1979, (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 42-43)
    - Glass, circa 1958-1979 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Graphics, circa 1950-1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Jewelry, circa 1945-1985, (10 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 33, Folder 3-12)
    - Jewelry Negatives, circa 1945-1985 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Lamps, circa 1945-1950 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Lithograph Prints, circa 1980 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Works of Art - Logging in Watercolors, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Models, circa 1963-1966 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Murals, circa 1943-1945, (8 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43) (Box 33, Folder 18-25)
    - Murals, circa 1943-1945 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Terra Cotta Casts, circa 1935-1942 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Sculpture in Glass and Copper, 1958-1989 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Sculpture Models for New Dehli Fountain, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Wire Sculpture, circa 1966 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Sculpture, circa 1940-1980, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 31-32)
    - Sculpture, circa 1940-1980 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Topological Structures, circa 1963-1977 (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Wall Paper, circa 1948 (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Wood, circa 1935-1995 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - Identified for Kauffman Fine Art, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Identified for Palm Springs Museum of Art, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Identified, circa 1943-1988, (9 folders) (Box 33, Folder 39-47)
    - Identified, circa 1935-1995, (10 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43 and 56) (Box 34, Folder 1-10)
    - Unidentified, circa 1935-1995, (25 folders, oversized items housed in Box 43 and OV 55) (Box 34, Folder 11-35)
    - Unidentified, circa 1935-1995, (9 folders) (Box 35, Folder 1-9)
    - Early Works of Art, circa 1931-1945 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Works of Art - by Woty Werner, circa 1946-1952 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Works of Art - by Frans Wildenhain, circa 1965 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Works of Art - by Wilhelm Wessel, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Works of Art - by I. Serpan, 1949-1954 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Works of Art - Mural on Washington Boulevard (not CF), 1985 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Works of Art - Other Artists, circa 1925-1985, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
    - Works of Art - Unidentified Negatives, circa 1935-1995, (8 folders) (Box 35, Folder 18-25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1933-1995, 8.8:
    This subseries contains an eclectic mix of images, including reference photographs for future art projects, photographs of students and their artwork, and miscellaneous images of glass blowing and casting.
    - Artistic Expression, circa 1965-1990 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Bay Bridge Foundations, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Beach Scenes, circa 1965-1980 (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Beach Scenes - Venice, California, circa 1985-1988 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Casting, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Glass Blowing, circa 1972 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Grafitti in Paris, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Guggenheim Foundation - Concepts for Public Sculpture for the Los Angeles Area, 1978-1979, (3 folders) (Box 35, Folder 33-35)
    - Bruce Howell Photographs, circa 1940-1980 (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Industrial Scenes, circa 1969-1975 (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Musee Cantini, circa 1980-1990 (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - Nature Scenes, 1975-1979 (Box 35, Folder 39)
    - May O'Donnell Set, circa 1985 (Box 35, Folder 40)
    - Student Work - Unidentified, circa 1940-1950 (Box 35, Folder 41)
    - Student Work - California Labor School, 1945 (Box 35, Folder 42)
    - Student Work - Mills College in Oakland, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 43)
    - Student Work - California School of Fine Arts, 1948-1949 (Box 35, Folder 44)
    - Student Work - University of Southern California - Idyllwild, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 45-46)
    - Student Work - Utah State University, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 47)
    - John Wagar Photographs, circa 1985-1995 (Box 35, Folder 48)
    - Water System Experiments for Fountains - Backyard of Ocean Front Walk Property, circa 1964 (Box 35, Folder 49)
    - Wine Labels - Ideas, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 50)
    - Oversized Claire Falkenstein, circa 1975-1977, (from Box 27, F. 3) (Box OV 56)
    - Oversized Claire Falkenstein with her Works of Art, circa 1935-1995, (from Box 27, F. 11) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Commission - Joseph Bransten Table, 1948, (from Box 28, F. 37) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Commission - Peggy Guggensheim Gate, circa 1961, (from Box 29, F. 12) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Commission - St. Basil's Church, Los Angeles - Window Screens, Doors, and Rectory Screen Construction, 1968-1969, (from Box 30, F. 4) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Jewelry, circa 1945-1985, (from Box 33, F. 3) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Murals, circa 1943-1945, (from Box 33, F. 18) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Identified, circa 1935-1995, (from Box 34, F. 1) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Unidentified, circa 1935-1995, (2 folders, from Box 34, F. 11) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Prints from Falkenstein's Film "Touching the Quick," 1949-1950 (Box 43)
    - Oversized Commission - Princess Pignatelli Grotto Gates in Rome, 1957, (from Box 29, F. 38) (Box 43)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Identified, circa 1935-1995, (from Box 34, F. 1) (Box OV 56)
    - Oversized Works of Art - Unidentified, circa 1935-1995, (from Box 34, F. 11) (Box OV 55)
- Artwork, circa 1937-1995, Series 9:; (Box 36-37, 44, 57; 2.0 linear feet)
  The majority of artwork consists of Falkenstein's sketchbooks, especially from the 1970s and 1980s when she returned to drawing. Also found here are preliminary sketches of specific projects, i including the Princess Pignatelli Gates and the Predator sculpture series. Artwork by other artists includes sketches by Mark Tobey.